{"data":[{"question":"A _________ man will catch at a straw.","a":"drowned","b":"to drown","c":"drowning","d":"being drowning","answer":"3","explain":"\n- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle \n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"55","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"The concert conducted by Karajan proved very ___.","a":"exciting","b":"excited","c":"to excite","d":"being excited","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Exciting: when word described is non-person \n- Excited: when word described is person","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"55","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"The gentleman sitting with his arms ___ was my boss.","a":"folding","b":"to fold","c":"folded","d":"being folded","answer":"3","explain":"\n- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle \n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"55","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"Beethoven wasted too much time ___ his symphony No. 9.","a":"composed","b":"being composed","c":"compose","d":"composing","answer":"4","explain":"\n- A present participle attributes a quality of action to the noun, which is viewed as undertaking the action \n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"55","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"___ all things into consideration, his life is a happy one.","a":"Taking","b":"Having taken","c":"Take","d":"To take","answer":"1","explain":"\n- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle \n- When a participle phrase introduces a main clause, separate the two sentence components with a comma","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"55","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"I saw Professor Lee _________ in the library last night-","a":"works","b":"to work","c":"working","d":"worked","answer":"3","explain":"\n- A present participle attributes a quality of action to the noun, which is viewed as undertaking the action \n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"55","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"A man was killed. \" Where is the body of the ___man ?\"","a":"murder","b":"murdered","c":"murdering","d":"having murdered","answer":"2","explain":"\n- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle \n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"55","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"The name Nebraska comes from the Oto Indian word \"nebrathka,\" ___ flat water.","a":"to mean","b":"meaning","c":"it means","d":"by meaning","answer":"2","explain":"\n- A present participle attributes a quality of action to the noun, which is viewed as undertaking the action \n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and modifies a word farther up in the sentence, you will need a comma ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"55","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"___ his answer, she sent the second letter.","a":"Receiving not","b":"Not to receive","c":"Not being received","d":"Not having received","answer":"4","explain":"- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle\u00a0\n- When a participle phrase\u00a0introduces a main clause, separate the two sentence components with a comma","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"55","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"},{"question":"Our school,___ on a hill, commands a fine view.","a":"located","b":"locating","c":"having located","d":"to locate","answer":"1","explain":"\n- A past participle views the noun as having undergone the action expressed by the participle \n- When a participle phrase introduces a main clause, separate the two sentence components with a comma","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"55","subcategorylv2":"3","type":"1"}]}